Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Occupy Wall Street Screen Printers Co-op Archived Website, May 13, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street Screen Printers Co-op
  Occupy Wall Street Screenprinters Co-op is a print production facility established during the initial occupation of Zuccotti Park by the Occupy Wall Street Movement in 2011. The money raised from the print shop during the occupation was used to General Assembly's General Fund and Occupy's Workers Cooperative. The co-op produces prints for Occupy events, custom print orders, and other community needs. The organization uses fair labor practices and prints on sustainable sourced clothing and materials. The co-op operates on a donation structure; products are on a pay-what-you-wish scale. The website contains a blog, a product line, their mission statement, and sustainability resources.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Screen process printing.
- Occupy Washington, DC Archived Website, Oct 25, 2011-Jul 4, 2013; Occupy DC
  October 2011 began as an informational website regarding a demonstration in McPherson Square in Washington DC in October 2011. It became an informational website related to the occupation in Freedom Plaza, which was in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street Movement. The website contains daily updates on the status of the occupation, a calendar of events, videos, and a blog.
  Financial sector of the American economy.; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility of business.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- OccupyWiki.org Archived Website, Oct 24, 2011-Jan 19, 2012; OccupyWiki.org
  A website with links to other Occupy websites.
- OccupyWishList.org Archived Website, Nov 5, 2011-Jan 19, 2012; MoveOn.org Civic Action
  Occupy Wish List is a craigslist-type website which lists materials and supplies needed by the Occupy Wall Street movement and sustain the occupations in cities throughout the country.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Social responsibility of business.; Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.
- Occupy with Art Archived Website, Nov 4, 2011-May 19, 2013; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  Formerly Occupenial, Occupy with Art, founded in 2011, is an affinity group of the Arts and Culture working group for the Occupy Wall Street movement. The group consists of artists who produce art, cultural events and projects with a particular focus on OWS as a social art process. The website serves as an information hub for current and past art-related activities in the OWS movement. The website contains a blog that provides updates on works in progress and event information, jobs posting, videos, and photos of art projects.
- OccupyWriters.com Archived Website, Oct 26, 2011- ongoing; Wall Street Writers
  Occupy Writers is a collection of writings by writers who support the Occupy Movement. The website contains short writings on observations, analysis, poetry, and prose on the occupy movement. The website links the names of writers and their writings contributed to the site.
  Financial sector of the American economy.; Authors |x Political activity.; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility of business.; Petitions.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Your Congress Archived Website, Jul 18, 2013-Jan 18, 2014; Occupy Congress
  Occupy Congress, established in late 2011, is a collective affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street street movement. The collective organized an action on January 17, 2012 with members of Occupy DC. The website contains meeting minutes, videos, event listings, action updates, and a blog.
  Washington (D.C.); Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Off Our Backs Archived Website, Jul 24, 2012-Apr 23, 2013; off our backs
  off our backs is a feminist news journal that was first published in 1970. Their mission is to provide news and information about women's lives and feminist activism, educate the public about the status of women around the world, serve as a forum for feminist ideas and theory, be an information resource on feminist, women's, and lesbian culture, and seek social justice and equality for women worldwide. The website features access to back issues.
  Feminism and mass media.
- OIG Testimony: June 4, 2008 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of the Inspector General
  Contains testimony of the Office of the Inspector General given on June 4, 2008 regarding the Federal Bureau of Investigation's observation of and involvement in detainee interrogations at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp.
  United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation |x Evaluation.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- OIG Testimony: June 10, 2008 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of the Inspector General
  Contains testimony of the Office of the Inspector General given before the Senate Committee on the Judiciary on June 10, 2008 regarding the Federal Bureau of Investigation's observation of and involvement in detainee interrogations at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp.
  United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation |x Evaluation.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Torture |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- Organization for Black Struggle Archived Website, Oct 2014 - ongoing; Organization for Black Struggle
  The Organization for Black Struggle was founded in 1980 by activists, students, union organizers and other community members in St Louis, Missouri, with the aim of building black power. The websites contains information about the organization's political platform, news and events, and the national mobilization against police violence following the 2014 police killing of Mike Brown in Ferguson, MO.
  Black power.; Police brutality.; St. Louis (Missouri)
- Organizing for Occupation | Housing Justice in NYC through Direct Action Archived Website, Oct 19, 2011- ongoing; Organizing for Occupation
  Organizing for Occupation (O4O) is a group of New York City residents from the activist, academic, religious, homeless, arts, and progressive legal communities to respond to the housing crisis. The group advocates affordable and safe housing for all. The group works through non-violent direct action to end homelessness and foreclosures. The website contains a calendar, a mailing list, and links page.
  Housing -- New York (N.Y.); Homeless persons |z New York (State) |z New York.
- OWS Direct Action Archived Website, Mar 24, 2012- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  OWS Direct Action is the action working group of the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website contains information on meetings, their direct action campaigns and days, their eco-action campaign, resources, and passed proposals.
- Paper Tiger Television Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010- ongoing; Paper Tiger Television Collective (Firm)
  Paper Tiger Television (PTTV), established in 1981, has been creating investigative and alternative media. The programs produced at PTTV inspire community productions and activism around the world. Its archive includes shows that provide critical analysis of media, educate about the communications industry and highlight issues that are absent from mainstream information sources. Through the production and distribution of public access series, media literacy/video production workshops, community screenings, videos on the website, and grassroots advocacy PTTV works to challenge and expose the corporate control of mainstream media. PTTV believes that increasing public awareness of the negative influence of mass media and involving people in the process of making media is mandatory for the long-term goal of information equity.
  Television -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Parents for Occupy Wall Street Archived Website, Oct 23, 2011-May 2, 2013; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  The parents for Occupy Wall Street website is a solidarity page of parents who support the Occupy movement. The website contains a blog, a campaigns page, and a videos page.
- Park West Village Tenants' Association Archived Website, Mar 13, 2012 - ongoing; Park West Village Tenants Association (New York, N.Y.)
  Park West Village Tenants' Association, first active in 1974, is a voluntary, non-profit, membership organization whose purposes are to protect the rights and welfare of tenants in Park West Village (PWV); keep PWV tenants informed of their rights; represent PWVTA members in negotiations with Park West managements; represent the concerns of PWVTA members to outside organizations and to elected officials and government agencies; and support and participate in campaigns by various organizations; to expand tenant rights; strengthen rent regulations; preserve affordable housing programs; and protect the ability of low-income and moderate-income tenants to remain in their homes. They are affiliated with Tenants and Neighbors and the Metropolitan Council on Housing. The website contains resources, a renters' guide, photos, and history.
- Party for Socialism and Liberation Archived Website, Aug 17, 2009-ongoing; Party for Socialism and Liberation (U.S)
  The Party for Socialism and Liberation, a revolutionary Marxist organization formed in 2004, seeks to bring together leaders and organizers to aim for revolution in the United States and promote socialism. They stand for defense of the existing workers' states, the national liberation movements, and for workers and oppressed people around the world. The website contains information on the Party for Socialism and Liberation in the United States, and its newspaper Liberation. The site features news and analysis of contemporary events, and reports from activists involved in the anti-war movement and labor movement, and other issues. The website also contains information on their campaigns and additional publications.
  Trotskyism -- United States.; Marcy, Sam, 1911-1998
- Peace Action Archived Website, Feb 25, 2010- ongoing; Peace Action (Organization)
  Peace Action (originally from the merger of the Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign and the Committee for a SANE Nuclear Policy), founded in 1987, is a national grassroots organization that organizes campaigns to end the nuclear threat, to create a more peaceful economy, and to support nonviolent resolutions to international conflicts. The website contains information on issues, news, action alerts, a media center, and a resources page.
- Peace Action New York State Archived Website, Feb 25, 2010- ongoing; Peace Action New York State
  Peace Action of New York State and the Peace Action Fund of New York State are the New York affiliates of Peace Action.
  Peace movements -- New York (State)
- Peace and Freedom Party Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009- ongoing; Peace and Freedom Party (U.S.)
  The Peace and Freedom Party is California's feminist socialist political party, founded in 1967. It is committed to socialism, democracy, ecology, feminism and racial equality. The website contains their by-laws, platform, newsletters, and news listings on current campaigns.
  Third parties (United States politics); Feminism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.
- People's World Archived Website, Aug 13, 2010- ongoing; People's World
  People's World, established online in 2009, is a national news website that reports on workers' rights, peace, equality, social and economic justice, democracy, civil liberties, women's rights, protection of the environment, and more. The website is affiliated with the Community Party USA and descended from the Daily Worker, the Communist Party's newspaper from 1924-1991. The website publishes articles and opinion pieces. The Spanish language edition of the website is called Mundo Popular.
  Communism -- Periodicals.; People's world
- People of Color / #OccupyWallStreet Archived Website, Nov 4, 2011- ongoing; People of Color at Occupy Wall Street
  People of Color, Occupy Wall Street is the tumblr blog created in response to the lack of racial diversity represented at the Occupy Wall Street occupations. Their goal is to develop critical consciousness within the movement and extend the movement's reach to include those most affected by the current crisis. The website lists working group meetings and sub committees of the working groups.
  Social responsibility of business.; Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- People of Color Organize Archived Website, Jul 28, 2009-Sep 11, 2013; Illvox
  People of Color Organize! was the successor to Illvox.org, established in June of 2007. In 2010, the URL changed to http://www.peopleofcolororganize.com/. Illvox supported Anarchist People of Color and its efforts. People of Color Organize! was a website journal and media source for activists who support direct action for social, racial, and economic justice. The website features debates, event listings, and commentary from the revolutionary left on matters of race, national oppression, and self determination efforts. People of Color Organize! focuses on people of color and their activism, community organizing, theory and perspectives. In 2013, this website was subsumed by the Party for Socialism and Liberation, which can be found in Tamiment's Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism Web Archive.
  Minorities -- United States.; Anarchism -- United States.
- Political Affairs Archived Website, Apr 9, 2013-ongoing; Political Affairs
  Political Affairs is an online magazine of theories, ideas, politics and culture of the socialist and democratic traditions and visions of the United States from a working- class point of view. The website features stories from the labor movement; from associations of every trade and profession; from the struggles of communities of color and diverse nationalities against racial injustice and inequality; and the movements of women, youth, seniors, the disabled, and of gay, lesbian, bi-sexual and transgender communities for equality. They seem to be affiliated with the Communist Party USA. The website contains sections on features, culture, editor's blog, education, and news analysis.
  Communism.; Alternative mass media.; Communist Party of the United States of America
- Practical Anarchy Magazine Archived Website, Jul 8, 2012-Apr 8, 2013; Practical Anarchy
  Practical Anarchy, founded in 1991, magazine is a quarterly publication that is published by the Alternative Media Project. The website contains articles and back issues.
- Progressive Labor Party Archived Website, Jul 29, 2009- ongoing; Progressive Labor Party
  The Progressive Labor Party (PLP), established in 1962, is a militant communist faction that works to eliminate capitalism and institute communism through a revolutionary movement and a mass Red Army. PLP organizes workers, students and soldiers to turn capitalism driven wars into a revolution for communism. The website contains issues of its newspaper, Challenge, multimedia, news postings and analysis, a history of the party, and a blog.
  Communism -- United States.
- Project South Archived Website, Jul 17, 2012- ongoing; Project South
  Project South is a Southern-based leadership development organization that uses popular education, partnership and alliances, and organizing to build political, educational, and economic power at the grassroots of low-income communities. The website contains information on their current projects and programs.
- ProLibertad Freedom Campaign Archived Website, Sep 28, 2007-Oct 14, 2011; ProLibertad Freedom Campaign
  ProLibertad Freedom Campaign was a support website for the Puerto Rican nationalists who were imprisoned in the United States for sedition in the early 1980s and Puerto Rican political prisoners in general. The organization worked to release the prisoners, eleven of which were offered clemency in 1999 by President Bill Clinton. As of 2013, one prisoner, Oscar López Rivera, remains in prisoner. The website was defunct by late 2011, at that point two other prisoners, Avelino Gonzalez Claudio, and Norberto Gonzalez Claudio, also remained in prison. It contains writings by the prisoners, a radio show, newsletters, video, and a history of the organization and cases.
  Political prisoners -- United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights.; Puerto Rico.
- Puerto Rico - Solidarity Network / Red Solidaria PR-SN Archived Website, Jul 7, 2011-Oct 7, 2012; Puerto Rico Solidarity Network
  The Puerto Rico Solidarity Network is an organization that works to inform and build support for the Puerto Rico working class labor, community, environment, and student grassroots struggles and also work to promote and develop connections in New York and across the United States.
  Working class -- Puerto Rico; Puerto Rico -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements
- Radical Art Caucus Archived Website, Nov 4, 2009-Nov 3, 2012; Radical Art Caucus
  The Radical Art Caucus' (RAC) primary mission is the promotion of art and art historical scholarship that addresses problems of oppression and possibilities for resistance. RAC seeks to provide an intellectual and professional environment for the discussion of labor and social justice issues specifically related to contemporary practices of art and art history.
  Art historians -- United States.; Art historians -- United States.; Art -- Political aspects.
- Radical History Review Archived Website, Mar 27, 2014-ongoing; Radical History Review
  The Mid-Atlantic Radical Historians Organization (MARHO) was formed during a conference at Fordham University in January 1973, attended mostly by professors at colleges and universities in the metropolitan New York area. he journal seeks to "address issues of gender, race, sexuality, imperialism, and class" and stretch "the boundaries of historical analysis to explore Western and non-Western histories." In addition to articles on the theme of any given issue, the journal is often comprised of sections dedicated to teaching and public history, as well as reviews of television, books, museum exhibitions, and other media. The website contains call for proposals for future issues, descriptions of recent issues, subject guides, and back issues.
  New Left -- United States.; Radicalism -- United States.; New Left -- United States -- Periodicals.; United States -- History -- Periodicals.; Radical history review; MARHO (Organization)
- Radical Philosophy Association Archived Website, Nov 29, 2008 - ongoing; Radical Philosophy Association
  Founded in 1982, the Radical Philosophy Association is an international organization whose members struggle against capitalism, racism, sexism, homophobia, disability discrimination, environmental ruin, and all other forms of domination, drawing upon a variety of radical traditions including phenomenology, Marxism, anarchism, post-structuralism, post-colonial theory and environmentalism. Its efforts center on conferences and publications. The RPA also publishes the journal Radical Philosophy Review.
  Philosophers |x Political activity.
- Radical Reference Archived Website, Nov 26, 2008 - ongoing; Radical Reference
  Radical Reference, launched in 2004, is a collective of library workers that support activist communities, progressive organizations, and independent journalists by providing professional research support, education, and access to information. The website provides reference to activists and independent journalists related to their activities.
  Librarians -- Political activity -- United States.; Reference and research services -- United States.
- Radical Women Archived Website, Dec 9, 2011- ongoing; Radical Women
  Radical Women (RW) is a socialist feminist, grassroots activist organization that provides a radical voice within the feminist movement and trains women to be leaders in the movements for social and economic justice. The organization promotes union action and international solidarity, combats racism in the women's movement and views capitalism as part of the reason why women are oppressed. Radical Women was founded in 1967 by Gloria Martin. It is affiliated with the Freedom Socialist Party (FSP). The website contains event notices and activities.
  Feminism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.
- Redstockings: Women's Liberation Studies Archives for Action Archived Website, Nov 10, 2009- ongoing; Redstockings, Inc.
  Redstockings was a name taken in 1969 by one of the founding women's liberation groups of the 1960's to represent the union of two traditions: the "bluestocking" label disparagingly pinned on feminists of earlier centuries--and "red" for revolution. Redstockings today is a grassroots, activist "think tank", for defending and advancing the women's liberation agenda. The Archives for Action is a project Redstockings established in 1989 to make the experiences of the 1960's movement more widely available for new understandings and improved strategies. The movement also supports a national health care system and equal job benefits for women.
  Redstockings.; Feminism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.
- Refuse & Resist! Archived Website, Mar 27, 2014; Refuse & Resist! (Organization)
  Refuse & Resist! was a human rights activist group founded in New York City in 1987. They opposed censorship, war, acts of police brutality, advocated against the death penalty and other acts of violence. They supported political prisoners, undocumented immigrants, the poor, and reproductive rights. Refuse & Resist! worked through nonviolent resistance, including speaking out in schools, communities and in the media; organizing forums and meetings; demonstrating in the streets; creating and performing cultural works; and contributing financially. The organization officially dissolved in 2006 and the website ceased updating in 2008. The website contains news listings, their CounterAttack magazine, and their artists network.
  Radicals |z United States |x Civil rights.; Human rights |z United States.; Prisoners -- Civil rights -- United States.; Peace movements -- United States.
- Reprieve Archived Websites, July 2009-ongoing; Reprieve.; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  Reprieve is a legal action non-profit that investigates, litigates, and campaigns against human rights abuses. Issues focused on include ending the death penalty, closing the Guantánamo Bay Prison, stopping illegal and lethal drones, ending the use of torture, and unlawful detention. The website contains casework, policy and research, media and reports, creative projects, action campaigns, petitions, and news. Reprieve and Reprieve US are two individual organizations but work closely together and share financial resources. Reprieve US focuses on litigation in the United States, whereas Reprieve focuses more globally.
- RevLeft Archived Website, Mar 16, 2010- ongoing; RevLeft.com
  RevLeft is a leftist chat forum, of over 10,000 leftists. The website fosters the discussion of news, politics, history, political theory, philosophy, music, literature, films from a leftist perspective. The website also contains a calendar of events.
  Online chat groups; Trotskyism.; Communism.; Anarchism.; Socialism
- Revolution: Voice of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA Archived Website, Aug 15, 2010-Aug 14, 2013; Revolutionary Communist Party, USA
  This is the official website for Revolution newspaper, voice of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA [A Maoist- inspired organization whose Chairperson is Bob Avakian]. This site was subsumed under the Revolutionary Communist Party website in early 2013.
  Maoism -- United States.; Avakian, Bob
- Revolutionary Communist Party, USA Archived Website, Sep 23, 2007- ongoing; Revolutionary Communist Party, USA